<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ruminations on Purveyor Of Curiosity</title>
    <link>https://karlstedman.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ruminations on Purveyor Of Curiosity</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 08:46:44 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://karlstedman.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Be Greedy</title>
      <link>https://karlstedman.com/blog/be-greedy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 08:46:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karlstedman.com/blog/be-greedy/</guid>
      <description>I have a tendency to revert back to my investing roots when the markets and economic situation turn “interesting”. We are definitely in an interesting period right now.
Today I wanted to touch on the psychological impact these times of turmoil have on investors. I have a unique perspective of being both on the investing side and the capital raising side for my startup. In both cases, markets and investors have retrenched, reducing the dollar amount and frequency of investments they are deploying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expanding Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://karlstedman.com/blog/expanding-perspectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 10:34:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karlstedman.com/blog/expanding-perspectives/</guid>
      <description>I like to speak and write on topics that are not traditionally covered. This is because I believe that a lot of the narratives that exist in most media are simplistic and written for the lowest common denominator. When one’s thought process is shallow and it comes time to assign blame (a typical, but misguided, social response), the reason cited is shallow as well. This is especially problematic in the election cycles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astronomical Shift</title>
      <link>https://karlstedman.com/blog/astronomical-shift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 10:03:11 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karlstedman.com/blog/astronomical-shift/</guid>
      <description>There is a massive shift happening right now in the Space ecosystem. A shift from Governmental driven focus and priorities, to a more privately driven one. This multi-decade shift is monumental in nature and the size of the impact is on course to challenge the internet as the most impactful economic change* in humanity’s history.
The reason behind this statement is very simple, it is one of the resources available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Work</title>
      <link>https://karlstedman.com/blog/the-future-of-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 08:31:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karlstedman.com/blog/the-future-of-work/</guid>
      <description>It seems like everywhere we turn these days there is a headline depicting the coming age of the destruction of the human-based workforce. AI art, automated factories, and many more examples come to mind and it may seem like your job isn’t safe anymore, and you’re right…
It isn’t…
Most likely the job you have right now will not look the same or will not be a job at all in 10 years, AND THAT IS A GOOD THING.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>*Litepulse New Logo*</title>
      <link>https://karlstedman.com/blog/litepulse-logo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 07:31:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karlstedman.com/blog/litepulse-logo/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to take a quick second to introduce Litepulse’s new branding to the world. The team did an amazing job! The new logo, colors, and icon capture the essence of Litepulse perfectly.
The gradient of colors signifies our use of multiple frequencies in our transmissions. The icon draws its inspiration from the wifi logo and signifies the transmission of power across vast distances. With the font, we wanted something clean and forward-looking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>*Space Is Hard*</title>
      <link>https://karlstedman.com/blog/space-is-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 09:07:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karlstedman.com/blog/space-is-hard/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Space is Hard&amp;rdquo;
If you have ever heard an interview about space you probably heard the phrase SPACE IS HARD&amp;hellip;
We need to stop saying that. Its an excuse. One that if we intend to become a multi-planet species we must change.
The history of space flight is short, roughly ~ 70 years at the time of this writing and in that time we have had many failures. These repeated failures have instilled the modality that space is hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>*Universal Truths*</title>
      <link>https://karlstedman.com/blog/universal-truths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 07:29:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karlstedman.com/blog/universal-truths/</guid>
      <description>In times of universal deceit, telling the truth is a revolutionary act.
-George Orwell
We are living in a time where lies are no longer considered wrong. They are told so much that people just accept it. The act of misleading has turned into an art form. This is truly one of the greatest travesties of our times. So in light of that background, I have decided to speak bluntly as possible…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>*Mental Valleys*</title>
      <link>https://karlstedman.com/blog/mentalvalleys/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 10:27:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karlstedman.com/blog/mentalvalleys/</guid>
      <description>As a human in an uncertain world, one always has to embrace learning and adapting. It is the essence of life and success. Heraclitus said it best:
“Change is the only constant in life”
The problem with a lot of modalities and assumptions is that we as a species tend to crowd think and use our most recent experiences as a reference for the future. Put simply we project the future in a linear fashion when the truth is that the future will be variable in ways we cannot predict.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>*Historical Waves*</title>
      <link>https://karlstedman.com/blog/waves/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 08:27:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karlstedman.com/blog/waves/</guid>
      <description>Mark Twain once said that “history never repeats itself, but it often rhymes.” This is as true now as it was then. I love to study history because if you know where we have been, you will be able to see the precursors of trends in where we are going.
When you go back in time and look at the maturation process of industries, from concept to maturation, they typically mature in three waves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>*Litepuse Is Born*</title>
      <link>https://karlstedman.com/blog/litepuse-is-born/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 10:51:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karlstedman.com/blog/litepuse-is-born/</guid>
      <description>How business and mission are conducted in the space ecosystem has been static for decades. Progress has been primarily driven by Governmental money and the finicky focus of politics. This has resulted in the stagnation of humanity’s progress toward the stars.
The good news is that this dynamic is changing rapidly. With the influx of private capital and focus, we are rapidly evolving the space ecosystem into a more dynamic and efficient organism.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
